Brandon Franklin

Boca Raton, Florida - 561.674.6225 - <u>brandon.h.franklin@gmail.com</u>

Objective:

Curate robust web applications utilizing the latest technologies and adhering to the highest of standards. Experienced with stages of web development including design concept and prototyping, through QA, deployment and release. Strong background in design theory and communicating with other teams.

Education:

Graduated 2011: Bachelors of Graphic Design, Digital Media Arts College, Boca Raton, FL

Delta Epsilon Iota Honor Society

Jan 2017 - Present: Pursuing Bachelors in Computer Science at FAU School of Engineering

- Intro to Programming in C, Foundations of CS, Logic Design

Work Experience:

Cendyn

Front End Developer, February 2016 - Present

- Collaborate with both UX Designers and Back End Developers
- Aid QA team in exploratory testing and business related defects
- Develop and maintain living UI kit

Production Manager, May 2015 – February 2016

- Implement, train and maintain industry best practices for CSS and HTML
- Monitored the status of each project and worked to ensure goals were met by the production team
- Proactively identified potential production challenges and provided solutions to prevent in the future
- Ensured proper communication between internal departments, Managers, and Customers
- Organized alerts and scheduled jobs for server maintenance, data processing, and deployments

Product Services Manager, July 2013 – May 2015

- Daily client interaction with Fortune 500 clients Starwood Hotels, Hilton Worldwide, Hyatt Hotels & Resort, IHG & Four Seasons Hotels, and many more
- Close interaction with advertising, design, sales, and programming teams to ensure cross departmental synchronization of projects and product launches
- Presented virtual product demos to educate clients and up-sell them on new product opportunities and software integration post sale
- Experience with creating, maintaining and updating SWOT Analyses, Project Flows (VISIO),
 SalesForce.com, FogBugz, and a multitude of other project management and ticketing systems
- Ongoing product enhancement & post live support

Production Coordinator, July 2012 - July 2013

- Expedite day to day operations by streamlining work-flow and delegating tasks to suit team member strengths
- Provide feedback regarding the organization's production, project and process management

Web Production Specialist, July 2011 - July 2012

- Build website templates for Fortune 500 clients

Brandon Franklin

Boca Raton, Florida - 561.674.6225 - brandon.h.franklin@gmail.com

<u>UserSight</u>

Web Design Associate, March 2011 – July 2011

- Create and maintain several custom websites for local South Florida businesses
- Comprehensive knowledge of 960.gs, color theory, composition, and typographical elements
- Monitor uptime for websites as well as identify, diagnose, troubleshoot issues, and implement solutions

Projects:

Hilton Worldwide Product Suite

- Responsible for the recruitment, training, and development of 4 new team members in an effort to increase productivity by the end of the year. The team was able to exceed expectations two-fold and deliver the final release of the project early and under budget.

Living UI Kit

- Worked with the UX Design team to cultivate a philosophy for rebranding the entire suite of 22 products. This involved conceptualization and prototyping items to include in the kit.
 - o Implementation
 - Testing
 - O A tutorial to guide new users on how to correctly use the kit
 - O Maintain the code base per updates from the designers

Skills:

Proficiencies

HTML, CSS, LESS/SASS Preprocessing, Bootstrap, Foundation, JavaScript, jQuery, Version Control (TFS, GIT), Responsive Web Design, Cross-Browser Compatibility, Adobe Creative Suite, Windows/MAC, VS Code, Atom, Working with Offshore/Remote Teams

Familiarizations

Angular 1x, React, ES6, MVC, ASP.NET, Node, NPM, Yarn, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Browserify, Unit Testing

Achievements & Interests:

Eagle Scout

BocaJS Meetup

Github open source contributor, UI fix for exercism.io